Inventory of the Austin-Twyman Papers, 1765-1939
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1765-1939. (Folder 1-159)
  - Letters to, from, or about the Twyman Family, 1811-1937, n.d. (Folder 22-125)
    - John A. Twyman, 1871-1937, n.d., 383 items. (Folder 86-105)
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1906., 17 items. (Folder 92)
        Letters to him as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. from James M. Thomas, Joseph Dupuy Eggleston, Courtney Irving, William G. Ransom. Includes letter, 11 January 1906, concerning Sally M. Smith (see folders 91 and 87).
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, January - February 1907., 34 items. (Folder 93)
        Includes letters to him as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. from James S. Thomas, Walter R. Smith, A. L. Smith, Willis A. Jenkins (concerning Virginia Education Exhibit of Jamestown Exposition), Joseph Dupuy Eggleston, E. H. Russell, James S. Thomas, J. S. Jarman (president State female Normal School, Farmville, Va., now Longwood College).
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, March - December 1907., 32 items. (Folder 94)
        Includes letters to him as Superintendent of Schools in Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include Willis A. Jenkins (concerning Jamestown Exposition), Joseph Dupuy Eggleston, James S. Thomas, William G. Ransom, Willie Sue Nicholas, Calva Watson, Lila Waller Duval, Charles M. Robinson, J. W. Hebditch, Hattie E. Forbes (concerning Sally M. Smith).
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1908., 26 items. (Folder 95)
        Includes letters to him as Superintendent of Schools in Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include Calva Watson, Willie Sue Nichols, A. L. Pitts, L. O. Prince, Jno. W. Prince, James S. Thomas, Love Hardy, Joseph D. Eggleston, J. W. Hebditch, G. W. Patteson, Wm. G. Ransom, Lila Waller Duval, Courtney Irving, W. B. Forbes, C. J. Morris, W. W. Haskins.
      - Letters to and about John A. Twyman, 1909., 23 items. (Folder 96)
        Includes letters to him as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include James B. Thomas, James H. Dilliard (concerning Jeanes Fund for black teachers), Joseph Dupuy Eggleston, T. E. Williams, Agnes White, H. Blankinship, Edna Wright, A. W. Carter, W. G. Edwards, Jackson Davis, Annie C. Coleman, A. W. Moore. Includes petitions requesting Twyman's reappointment as Superintendent.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1910-1912., 8 items. (Folder 97)
        Includes letters to him as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include O. J. Morgan, Nannie Baldwin, Calva Watson, Anna Roy[ster ?] Rogers, Eliza [?] (deciding not to marry Twyman because if her mother's objections), Plummer F. Jones (Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va.)
      - Letters about John A. Twyman, 1913., 50 items. (Folder 98)
        Letters to State Board of Education from W. L. Boatwright, A. H. Clement, A. C. Garnett, George Braxton Taylor, E. V. Anderson, A. S. Hall, Frank P. Brent, Sands Gayle requesting that Twyman be appointed again as school superintendent in place of Plummer F. Jones. Includes petitions.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1914., 22 items. (Folder 99)
        Include letters written to Twyman as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. and to R. C. Stearns, Virginia Superintendent of Public Instruction. Correspondents include Florence L. Pettit, W. W. Haskins, Joseph W. Everett, Jno. B. Terrell, C. G. Baughan, R. F. Andrews, D. A. Christie, Jackson Davis, Joe B. [Davis ?], Sands Gayle, C. J. Holsinger, E. E. Worrell.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1915., 19 items. (Folder 100)
        Include letters written to Twyman as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include Everett E. Worrell, H. L. Webb (to W. W. Haskins), Joseph W. Everett, R. C. Stearns. Includes regulations and grading system of Arvonia High School, 1915-1916.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1916-1926., 22 items. (Folder 101)
        Include letters written to Twyman as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include Harris Hart, J. A. C. Chandler (asking that teachers be paid even though school sessions were shortened because of the influenza epidemic of 1918), Chandler & Blakey, Jno. P. McConnell, G. L. Brown, Arthur D. Wright, W. W. Haskins, George Braxton Taylor, Olivia L. Wyson (to P. P. Glover), Harris Hart (to Frank T. West), Josephine White, [Edward ?] C. Spencer, Polly Garnett Saunders, nan Edwards, James W. Wigginton, Harry F. Byrd (concerning Shenandoah National Park). Includes wedding announcement; and minutes, 1925, of Democratic County Committee.
      - Letters to and about John A. Twyman, 1927., 12 items. (Folder 102)
        Include letters to Twyman as Superintendent of Schools, Buckingham County, Va. Correspondents include Claude R. Wood, W. J. Hubard, G. L. Morris (and A. J. Terill and A. W. Carter to Morris), Edyth Jenkins, Carey M. Scales, R. S. Burruss, A. H. Trent.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1928-1929., 16 items. (Folder 103)
        Letters concerning Anti-Smith Democratic Movement. Correspondents include Lewis Twyman, J. Sidney Peters, Frank B. Dunford, G. W. M. [Taylor ?], J. Dwight Martin, James Cannon. Includes speech by T. N. Hass.
      - Letters to John A. Twyman, 1930-1936., 10 items. (Folder 104)
        Mostly concern Republican party politics. Correspondents include Dr. P. E. Tucker, L. F. Harris, Emmett D. Gregory, J. W. Blackwell, Harry F. Byrd. Includes broadside, 1930, entitled "Notice to the Republican voters of Buckingham County."
      - Letters to John A. Twyman (in Miami, Florida), 1937, n.d., 21 items. (Folder 105)
        Correspondents include Grover Hudgins, Cora Wood, Lilliam Eldridge, Russell Moon, Gertrude Sadler, Harry Byrd, Carter Glass, Rebekah Ellis, Hunter McGuire (dictated), Charles M. Barrell. Letters from Byrd and Carter Glass thank Twyman for opposition to packing U. S. Supreme Court.
    - Samuel Rodgers Twyman, 1871-1930, n.d., 229 items. (Folder 106-118)
      - Letters by Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1871-1877., 10 items. (Folder 106)
        To his brother Iverson L. Twyman or John A. Twyman. Concern family's poverty.
      - Letters by and about Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1881-1930., 17 items. (Folder 107)
        Includes letters to John A. Twyman, 1881-1882. Other letters concern Austin and Twyman genealogy.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1879-1906., 18 items. (Folder 108)
        Correspondents include Addison Spencer, Alice H. Bagby, L. F. Walker, W. R. Twyman, Iverson Twyman (of Bonham, Texas), Lizzie Twyman, C. Humphry, Julia Shipp, W. G. Stanard (concerning membership in the Virginia Historical Society), Lou. E. Twyman, John M. Daniel, Sm. L. [Clothworthy ?], John Lamb. Concern genealogical inquiries on Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1907-1909., 32 items. (Folder 109)
        Correspondents include R. L. D. McAllister, Robert O. Garrett, Thomas M. Green, H. J. Eckenrode, William F. Bagby, Carl A. Lewis, John C. Underwood, George Braxton Taylor, Mrs. F. Handy, Anna Royster Rogers, James Y. Lloyd, Jno. W. Richardson, W. R. Twyman, E. V. Anderson, H. R. McIlwaine, George E. Booker, Lillie Beall Lewis, Ruth Beall, Jackson Davis (bears letter of Plummer F. Jones), E. W. Twyman. Concern genealogical inquiries on Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1910., 22 items. (Folder 110)
        Correspondents include Ruth Beall, Sands Gayle, H. Silverthorn Co., Benjamin Twyman, M. A. Twyman, H. R. McIlwaine, H. J. Eckenrode, Nusbaum Book & Art Co., Mrs. M. A. Twyman, Daphne A. Carter. Concern genealogical inquiries on Twyman family and Twyman crest.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1911., 26 items. (Folder 111)
        Correspondents include Benjamin Twyman, Nusbaum Book & Art Co., Champ Clark, Margaret Huff (paper bears Twyman-coat-of-arms), D. W. Twyman, Jr., Thomas S. Martin, Leila C. Handy, Mrs. M. A. Twyman, Ruth Beall, Jno. C. Underwood, G. W. D. Twyman, Anna Roy[ster] Rogers, Sands Gayle, Lillie Geall Lewis. Concern genealogical inquiries on the Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1912., 16 items. (Folder 112)
        Correspondents include Leila C. Handy, Jno. C. Underwood, The Genealogical Association [William A. Crozier], Benjamin Twyman, Augusta G. Twyman (in Rome, Italy), Margaret H. Concern genealogical inquiries of Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1913-1914., 10 items. (Folder 113)
        Correspondents include Leila C. Handy, Anna Roy[ster] Rogers, Jno. C. Underwood, Ruth Beall, Mrs. R. J. Gilbert. Concern genealogical inquiries of Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1915-1916., 14 items. (Folder 114)
        Correspondents include Benjamin Twyman (enclosing photos), Mrs. R. J. Gilbert, H. D. Flood (concerning statue in Richmond to George Rogers Clark), J. M. Street, Laura K. Crozier, [?] Nichols, Fannie Twyman Gilbert. Concern genealogical inquiries of Twyman family.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1917-1919., 17 items. (Folder 115)
        Correspondents include Mary Twyman Klayder, Lewis Twyman, Margaret Huff, Mrs. Robert J. Gilbert, I. M. S., William Ellyson (for State Mission Board of Baptist General Association), W. R. Boyd, Jr. (League to Enforce Peace), David Hepburn (Anti-Saloon League and pamphlet - Liquor vs. Life: Anarchy vs. Law by George W. McDaniel. Letters concern World War I, Influenza Epidemic of 1918.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1920-1923., 22 items. (Folder 116)
        Correspondents include Mary Twyman Klayder, Ruby M. Naylor, Oliver J. Sands, H. R. McIlwaine, Julia Twyman, George E. Booker, Duval Porter, C. M. Barrell, Effle E. Carney, Mrs. R. J. Gilbert, Arthur Kyle Davis, David Hepburn (Anti-Saloon League), Julien Gunn, J. H. Lewis, J. E. West, L. E. Mauch, Mildred Jones Lewis (concerning Lewis Association). Many letters concern genealogical inquiries of Twyman family and death of Augusta Twyman.
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, 1924-1925., 17 items. (Folder 117)
        Correspondents include Nettie [?], Mrs. Richard Floyd burke, James William Wigginton, Ruth Beall, Mrs. Robert J. Gilbert, Buford Twyman, Mary Twyman Klayder, H. F. Byrd (announcing his candidacy for governor), Eula May Burke, George Braxton Taylor, W. J. Hubard (concerning Lee Last Camp Association.)
      - Letters to Samuel Rogers Twyman, n.d., 8 items. (Folder 118)
        Correspondents include Kate M. Cannon, Margaret Beale, James Lewis (English dog postcard), Lillie [?], Jamie Rouston Boulware, Kate M. Cannon, Mary T. Klayder.
    - Augusta G. Twyman, 1863-1920, n.d., 84 items. (Folder 119-121)
      - Letters by Augusta G. Twyman, 1871-1879., 23 items. (Folder 119)
        Letters written to Iverson L. Twyman (concerning teaching and the family's poverty), Bettie [?], Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, [Seymour W.] Holman.
      - Letters by Augusta G. Twyman, 1880-1885., 31 items. (Folder 120)
        Letters written to Iverson L. Twyman, Mabel B. Twyman, Samuel R. Twyman, Addie Walker.
      - Letters to Augusta G. Twyman, 1863-1920, n.d., 30 items. (Folder 121)
        Letters written by Louise E. Twyman, Daphne [?], Benjamin Twyman, V[irginia] Aldridge, S. F. Kitchen, Lucy Twyman (describing Episcopal Home in Richmond), M. V. Scruggs, M. M. Ellis, M. G. Carter, Ella Watson, Julia W. [Viditz?], L. F. Walker, [Nettie ?] Wright. Includes booklet (The Light of Christmastide).
    - Julia Twyman, 1914-1920., 17 items.
      Letters by and to Julia Twyman. Correspondents include her mother, Uncle John Twyman, letter of recommendation of her as a teacher, Florida teaching certificates, M. Gordon Twyman while studying law at the University of Virginia.
    - Mabel B. Twyman, 1872-1895, 46 items. (Folder 123-124)
      - Letters by Mabel B. Twyman, 1872-1895., 29 items. (Folder 123)
        Correspondents are Iverson L. Twyman, John A. Twyman (one letter bears note by Iverson L. Twyman; most letters written while she was attending State Normal School, Nashville, Tenn., [now Peabody College]), Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Augusta G. Twyman (concerning Mabel Twyman's ill-health, Dr. Edward McGuire, Dr. Hunter McGuire, streetcars in Richmond), Dr. Hunter McGuire.
      - Letters to Mabel B. Twyman, 1886-1895. (Folder 124)
        Letters written from Nellie [?].
    - Miscellaneous Twyman material, 1811-1937, n.d., 15 items.
      Photograph of Jack Twyman (as Lorenzo in "Merchant of Venice"), spiritual autobiography (copy), 1811, of George Twyman. Letters of Julia [?] and A. S. H. to Mary Lavinia Twyman, Alexander H. Sands (to Dr. William P. Twyman), Lizzie Twyman, Ben Twyman, Mrs. John Eldridge and Grover Hudgins to Lewis Twyman, Emmett D. Gregory, M. Gordon Twyman (to Edith Twyman and Julia Twyman), Mrs. M. V. Ayres, Belle [?] to Pa.
  - Letters to, from, or about the Horsley Family, 1834-1859. (Folder 126-130)
    - Various Horsley Letters, 1840-1849, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 126)
      Letter of E. P. Richardson to sister Ann S. Horsley, 1840, concerning qualms of her husband concerning slavery; letters, n.d., of A. E. Horsley, letters, 1849 and n.d., of F. C. Horsley to Iverson L. Twyman (concerning his not being appointed to faculty of U. Va.: "The faculty always intended to make their selections from the lower classes...They wanted to conciliate ragtag & bobtail because ragtag & bobtail vote for the delegates and the delegates vote for the annuity); John Horsley to James M. Spiller.
    - Mary Lavinia Horsley, 1837-1838, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 127)
      Letters, 1837 and n.d., written by Mary Lavinia Horsley to Henry Rodes. Letters, 1837-1838, of Henry A. Cabell and Henriann Cabell to Mary Lavinia Horsley. Mary Lavinia Horsley was the first wife of Iverson L. Twyman (1810-1864). They were married in Nov. 1838; she died in 1844.
    - Rebecca P. (Horsley) Austin, 1853, n.d., 6 items. (Folder 128)
      Letters, 1853 and n.d. by Rebecca P. (Horsley) Austin to Geo. B. Austin (concerning her separation from Austin) and to Iverson L. Twyman concerning her separation. Letters to Rebecca P. (Horsley) Austin.
    - Various Horsely Lettters, 1834-1853., 7 items. (Folder 129)
      Correspondence, 1834-1853, of Robert Y. Horsley with to Iverson L. Twyman, Rebecca P. (Horsley) Austin, George Austin and Lorenzo Norvell. Includes letter of Rebecca P. (Horsley) Austin to George B. Austin.
    - Doctor William A. Horsley, 1838-1859, 7 items. (Folder 130)
      Correspondence, 1838-1859, of Doctor William A. Horsley with Iverson L. Twyman (concerning Horsley's study of medicine at MCV) and William H. Summerell (concerning graduation at a medical school in Philadelphia).
  - Letters to, from, or about the Spiller Family, 1837-1889. (Folder 131-149)
    - Various Spiller Letters, 1851-1883, n.d., 15 items. (Folder 131)
      2 letters, Margaret Miller to Antonia (Tony) Spiller, 1868-1869. (In 1884 she married Iverson L. Twyman [1849-1921]. Letter, n.d., by Hampden Spiller to George Spiller. Letters, 1851-1883 & n.d., of Mary Frances Spiller to Iverson L. Twyman [bear letters of J. M. Spiller], Mrs [?] Bocock and letter, 1903, by F. G. Woodson to Mary F. Spiller.
    - Various Spiller Letters, 1849-1855, n.d., 36 items. (Folder 132)
      Letters, 1849, by G. A. Spiller to I. L. Twyman and James M. Spiller, George Spiller (while a student at VMI in 1862, working for New Orleans, Mobile and Texas Railroad, Mobile, Ala., Mobile and Ohio Railroad, Jackson, Tennesse; Texas Investment Co., Ltd., Fort Worth, Texas; Cattle Raisers Association, Jacksboro, Texas; Daily and Weekly Gazette, Fort Worth, Texas) to James M. Spiller and Mary Francis Spiller. Letters, 1855-, written to George Spiller by Charles B. Stewart, J. A. Kinnter, C. W. Figgat, L. W. Frazer, John Dooley.
    - J. M. Spiller, 1837-1889., 219 items. (Folder 133-148)
      - Letters by J.M. Spiller, 1847-1849., 9 items. (Folder 133)
        Letters by J. M. Spiller, Guard Lock No. 4, James River & Kanawha Canal. One, 2 October 1848, is a detailed account of appearance and conversations of Thomas Hart Benton. Other letters concern politics, [Spiller's hatred of Whigs], slavery ["I did not intend you to make a cook of Sally. Please leave her to herself to attend to the cows and her business - the women who suckle can and must cook"] and requesting Twyman's aid in keeping Spiller's sister from going back to her former husband.
      - Letters by J.M. Spiller, 1850-1853., 13 items. (Folder 134)
        Letters written by J. M. Spiller to Iverson L. Twyman and George B. Austin concerning slaves (buying and selling) and farm management.
      - Letters by J.M. Spiller, 1854-1855., 15 items. (Folder 135)
        Letters of J. M. Spiller to Iverson L. Twyman (one letter bears letter of Mary F. Spiller to Twyman), John H. Johnson, William McCorkle, H. Johns.
      - Letters by J.M. Spiller, 1856-1864, n.d., 16 items. (Folder 136)
        Letters by J. M. Spiller to Iverson L. Twyman, Pauline V. Reid, Virginia J. McDowell, William A. Glasgow. Letters concern Civil War.
      - Letters by J.M. Spiller, 1865-1880., 11 items. (Folder 137)
        Letters by J. M. Spiller to Martha E. (Austin) Twyman, Iverson L. Twyman, and S. M. Bocock, concerning Reconstruction, povery of Twyman family and Readjusters.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1837-1858., 18 items. (Folder 138)
        Letters from C[hapman] Johnson, George Booker, F. Jones, John A. Cooke, Josiah Samuel, Charles T. Bocock (concerning separation from Sarah Ann (Spiller) Bocock (concerning disposition of slaves and her ex- husband Charles T. Bocock), Mathew McDaniel, Henry Loving (concerning settling blacks in Ohio), Holison Johns, Walter Gwynn, Eliza Carrington, John J. Grasty.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1859-1861., 24 items. (Folder 139)
        Letters written by Eliza H. Carrington, D. P. Gooch, J. D. Davidson, H. C. Snyder, Reuben Sorrel (disposition of slaves), B. T. Stanley, N. H. Massie.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1862-1869., 21 items. (Folder 140)
        Letters written by A. H. Benson (of 11th Va. Infantry Regiment ?, bears drawing of engagement at Dranesville, Va., 20 December 1861), B. C. Megginson, N. F. Bocock, B. M. DeWitt, J. D. Davidson, T. Henry Thompson, [?] Rowland, Jones & Miller, Lynchburg, Va., F[rancis] H[enney] Smith (concerning supplies in 1865 for Virginia Military Institute), H. S. Lochery, George T. Lyle, John S. Grasty, B. Gould, A. C. Smith, Hall A. Winston & Co., Baltimore, Md., E. F. Blair.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1870-1872., 15 items. (Folder 141)
        Letters written by J. W. Walkup, Ben A. Donald (describing his recommendations for stuccoing), B. C. Megginson, Edward J. Chaffin, W. A. Deas (treasurer of VMI), Jno. K. Watkins, B. Gould, John T. Bocock, Charles A. Davidson, John S. Grasty (Presbyterian minister).
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1873-1876., 11 items. (Folder 142)
        Includes letters from John S. Grasty (Presbyterian minister), S. M. Bocock, Elliott Spiller (while student at Hampden-Sydney College and including report) and M. N. Hylum (bears seal of and concerns Patrons of Husbandry, State Grange of Va.)
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1877., 23 items. (Folder 143)
        Many letters about death of Elliott Spiller by gunshot wound at Hampden-Sydney College. Other letters concern Patrons of Husbandry, State Grange of Virginia. Correspondents include John A. Preston, William M. McPheeters, J. M. Blanton, D. W. Sparks, M. N. Hayburn, J. M. R. Sprinkel, Charles J. Jones, C. M. Reynolds, John F. White, L. T. Wilson, Frank G. Ruffin, William B. Cowper, Mary E. K. Damson, J. B. Seeley, Snow & Johnson, [n. p.]
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1878-1879., 10 items. (Folder 144)
        Letters written by A. F. Robertson, John T. Grasty (Presbyterian minister), William Mahone (calling a conference of Readjusters), Fannie Hamilton.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1880-1881., 11 items. (Folder 145)
        Letters written by John T. Grasty (Presbyterian minister), John F. White, William E. Cameron, Frank G. Ruffin (concerning election of ? and his own office in state government), J. M. Reynolds.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1882-1883., 16 items. (Folder 146)
        Letters written by John F. White (d. 1883), S. V. Reid, Mary Jasper Bocock, John S. Grasty (Presbyterian minister), Dr. James Madison Blanton, Jno. Henry Loving, George Hylton, William A. White.
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1884-1887., 15 items. (Folder 147)
        Letters written by Fleming Harris (former slave in Mt. Pleasant, Ohio), Charles J. Jones, J. M. Harris, S. T. Young, Ro[bert] F. Mays, W. G. Payne, William L. Royall, R. W. Glass, Catherine E. Phelps, William Mahone (letters, 25 June 1886 and 16 October 1887; concerning tariff and providing campaign strategy to Joseph B. Buhoman in his race against [?] Figgatt).
      - Letters to J.M. Spiller, 1888-1889, n.d., 15 items. (Folder 148)
        Letters written by Catherine E. Phelps, R. W. Glass, William Mahone (Republican patronage), W [Skeny ?], Fulvia [?], P. H. McCaull, Robert M. Hudson, C. W. Humphreys, Elliott Spiller, James Spiller (grandson).
    - Various Spiller Letters, 1850-1882., 8 items. (Folder 149)
      Letters written by or addressed to Sue M. Payne, Caroline Spiller, Emma Spiller, H. B. Spiller, J. H. Spiller, James Spiller, P. H. Spiller, I. L. Twyman.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1769-1930, n.d. (Folder 150-159)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1796-1809., 16 items. (Folder 150)
      Letters written by or addressed to Dudley Brooke, Edward Cunningham, Joseph Curd, Joseph Davis, Alexander Fulton, James Govan, Mary (Twyman) Greenwood (b. 1733 - copy), Micajah [?], Henry McClurg, Jonathan Maxey, Richard North, Richard C. Potter, Richard Phelps, Thomas Pleasants (Quaker), Charles H. Saunders, John Seayres, Reuben Sims (issuing slave pass), George Twyman, Dr. James Walker, Willis Wills, Hill & Rea.
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1810-1819., 20 items. (Folder 151)
      Letters written by or addressed to Christopher Anthony, John Baskerville, J. Bolling, David Bondurant, Jeffrey Bondurant, George Booker, Thomas Boulware, William Dunford, Henry Flood, Walter L. Fontaine, Charles Garrote (or Garrott), James T. Hubard, Ben Maxey, Jacob Maxey, Jonathan Maxey, Zachariah Nevit, J. Pittman, Thomas E. Pleasants, Philip Slaughter, John Taylor of Caroline (2 letters written by him), Mutual Assurance Society, Messrs. Scott & Gilliam, Ca Ira, Va.
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1820-1829., 22 items. (Folder 152)
      Many letters are permissions for slaves to join Mulberry Grove Baptist Church or are letters of dismissal from churches. Include letters written by or addressed to George Booker, James Christian, John Couch, R. Eldridge, Jr., Levy Gibson (petition to get out of jail), J. P. Gipson, D. Guerrant, William Horsley, James T. Hubard, James Jones, W. B. Jones, Peter Klipstine, Richard G. Morris (agrees to slaves being baptized, but objects to their being immersed in November), William Moseley, William P. Moseley, Mildred Rose, Poindexter P. Scott, Seymour Scott, Frances W. Talbot, Isham Talbot, Frances W. Taylor, M. P. Thomas, Jno. M. Walker (bears opinion of Benjamin Watkins Leigh), Gilbert Walker, Warner Williams, Charles Yancey, and the Mulberry Grove Baptist Church.
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1830-1839., 13 items. (Folder 153)
      Includes letters concerning slaves joining the church. Letters written by or addressed to W. Alexander, [?] Austen, William H. Carter (slave Patty), [?] M. Hollingsworth, Josias Jones, Thomas Jones, S. H. Laughlin, Jacob Maxey, William B. Maxey, R. E. Moseley, Reuben B. Patterson (slave), Charles Perrow, Robert A. Phelps, Robert Rives, Moses Spencer (concerning slave) and Lewis C. Tindall (concerning slave).
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1840-1849., 13 items. (Folder 154)